NICKOLAS MENOTTI

San Diego, CA

Phone: 760.443.0056 | **Email:** nmenotti@cox.net **LinkedIn:** https://www.linkedin.com/in/nickolas-m-b3490299

GitHub: https://github.com/Nmenotti20

Portfolio: https://nmenotti20.github.io/Responsive_Portfolio

SUMMARY

Full-Stack Web Developer with certificate from U.C. San Diego Extension Program Coding Bootcamp in Web Development Methods. Experience in retail operations management and an enthusiasm for continuously acquiring new skills and knowledge. Highly skilled at creativity and problem solving. Dedicated to developing user friendly applications. Appreciated by teammates for strong attention to detail with the flexibility to rapidly adapt to changing priorities regardless of complexity.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

DOM manipulation, C.R.U.D. operations, progressive we applications, agile methodology, computer science, database theory

LANGUAGES

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, Express, Handlebars, React, Node Js, NPM, MongoDB, MySQL and Git

APPLICATIONS

Git Bash, VS Code, MySQL Workbench, Postman, Heroku, GitHub, AWS, SalesForce, Slack, Zoom, MS Teams, Calendly

PROJECTS

MomAndPop | Link to GitHub: https://github.com/Nmenotti20/MomAndPop | Link to Deployed Project: https://momandpop2021.herokuapp.com/

- **Description:** Website similar to Yelp to promote local small businesses. The site allows business owners to post their business profile information while also allowing shoppers to rate experiences with small businesses and post comments on a business profile page.
- Role: Project Concept, User-Flow, Front-End Development, and assistance with Back-End DB
- **Technologies:** HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ReactJS, Bootstrap, JSON Web tokens, Socket.io, Node.JS, MySQL/ Sequelize, API, Axios.

OUTDoorsy | Link to GitHub: https://github.com/Jruuuu/OUTDoorsy.git/ | Link to Deployed Project: https://jruuuu.github.io/OUTDoorsy/

- **Description:** Website for outdoor adventure where users may search a city to find hiking trails near that city so they can get a little exercise. The site uses APIs to display current local weather conditions, find local hiking trails, and display the location of the trails on a map.
- Role: Front-End Development, Google Map API
- **Technologies:** HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bulma.io, Bootstrap, www.hikingproject.com Hiking Project API, https://openweathermap.org/api Open Weather API, https://developers.google.com/documentation/javascript/overview Google Map API,

Fur-EVER Home | Link to GitHub: https://github.com/TJH1992/Project-2.git | Link to Deployed Project: https://oursuperduperawesomeproject2.herokuapp.com/

- **Description:** Website created for a pet adoption agency that allows pet owners to search for a pet to adopt from their local area, as well as post pets up for adoption.
- Role: Front-End Development, assistance with Back-End DB
- **Technologies:** HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node, Express-Handlebars, Bootstrap, NPM, MySQL, https://www.petfinder.com/developers/v2/docs/ Pet Finder API

EXPERIENCE

Food Service Director Aramark

November 2012 – Present San Marcos, CA

Oversite of multi-unit contract managed dining operations within the Higher Education lines of business. Responsible for satisfying clients' requisites by providing comprehensive dining services to clients and their communities. Conduct regular client surveys for the purpose of soliciting candid feedback on our partnership and offerings in order to develop and implement action plans to improve the final product. Promote local marketing events to highlight services, gain brand loyalty, and drive revenue. Direct reports included one salaried manager, two salaried non-exempt employees and up to 40 hourly employees. Additional responsibilities include hiring, training and managing multiple teams in multiple locations, HR, and P&L accountability.

Key Accomplishments:

- Launched and provided support for cloud-based eCommerce applications for purchasing Declining Balance, and Catering services.
- Successfully negotiated contract extension with client.

Restaurant Manager California Pizza Kitchen

July 2007 – November 2012 San Diego, CA

Operations Management of one of the top ten revenue producing locations in the company with \$5.2M annual sales. Hired, trained, and developed opening staff of 120 people for new store opening in Las Vegas, NV. Achieved number 3 revenue spot in the nation with over \$86,000 incremental sales brought in through local marketing fundraiser events in 2011. Service and sales team motivation through daily contests, positive incentives, and public recognition to make it fun and competitive while improving performance.

Key Accomplishments:

- Launched and supported cloud-based take-out order eCommerce application for purchasing takeout food, and Catering Services.
- Provided local technical support for P.O.S. systems as needed.

EDUCATION

Coding Bootcamp Certificate in Web Development Methods: U.C. San Diego Extension Program

September 2020 – March 2021 San Diego, CA

Successful completion of 240-hour intensive instruction program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Bachelor of Arts in Economics: California State University, San Marcos, CA

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

United States Marine Corps, Veteran: Formerly held Secret Level Security Clearance.